

Test-Driven Frontend Web Developer okenochile@yahoo.com 0727505840

Nairobi, Kenya

Stephen Omollo

Profile

I believe technology involves connecting hardware, software, & intelligent manpower to achieve a certain goal/milestone. I offer creative-problem solving skills with over 4 years experience in system analysis, front-end web development, & web application testing. My working mantra is "Functional collaboration & continuous exploration of critical knowledge & skills."

Employment History

Test-Driven Frontend Web Developer at SereneStudy E-Learning , Nairobi, Kenya

08/2019-Present

Contributed to the development of SereneStudy E-Learning platform, over 30 e-commerce, multi-platform responsive websites, & landing pages.//Tested, debugged, & shipped 10s of 1000s of lines of code to various development teams.//Maintained graphic standards & branding throughout product interfaces resulting to over 80% positive customer feedback.//Performed unit & functional web application testing resulting in around 98% bug reduction.//Performed design reviews for continuous improvement in meeting client goals & needs leading to 90% client satisfaction rate.

Frontend Web Developer at Wavegaze Technologies LTD, Nairobi, Kenya

07/2017-02/2019

Followed SDLC & Agile best practices to produce rapid iterations for clients, increasing the delivery speed by over 30%.//Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals & design best practices resulting to over 85% client satisfaction rate.//Guided customers on project stages & iterations with input on best practices, user needs & technology capabilities reducing the rate of major modifications of the final product to below 20%.//Produced over 20 multi-platform websites & landing pages.//Performed UX QA testing increasing user acceptance rate to over 80%.//Coded using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, & React libraries to develop features for both mobile & desktop platforms thus increasing user access rate by over 30%.

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/okenostephen/ https://github.com/NairobiTester

Skills

Test-Driven Programming HTML/CSS/JavaScript MERN package jQuery Redux Angular.js Bootstrap and Tailwind SQL and NoSQL databases Ionic Framework Jest/Enyzme/Selenium Agile/Scrum

Interests

Web Design & Development
Software Testing
AWS & Docker
Python (Rest APIs, GraphQL APIs,
Microservices, Artificial Intelligence &
Datascience)
Rapid Learning Opportunities
Entrepreneurship
Leadership

Education

BS Information Technology (2009-2014), Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology